PRITESH NEELESH ZAVERI

SENIOR UI DEVELOPER

<u>Phone</u>: +1 (647) 724-1079 <u>Address</u>: Markham ON L6B1A8

<u>Email</u>: priteshzaveri27@gmail.com <u>Website</u>: www.priteshzaveri.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Goal-oriented Senior UI Developer with 4+ years of experience in building more than 28 responsive websites, 12 blogs, 5 data dashboards, REST APIs, HTML e-mailers, Web Components, Highly optimized landing pages, and Ad integrations for the Ad Tech industry. Used various web development languages and software to develop customer-focused websites and designs. Committed to high standards of web development, user experience, usability, speed, and browser support for all major browsers with backward compatibility up to IE 9.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Media.net Software Services (India) Pvt. Ltd

Mumbai, India

Senior UI Developer | UI Developer

07/2019 - Present 12/2017 - 06/2019

- · Converted PSD and Zeplin designs to Web pages using HTML, CSS, and Javascript.
- Created 15 WordPress websites with custom themes built from scratch, 17 Product websites built on CakePHP framework, and 8 Product Listing and Comparison Websites made using ReactJs in the Front-end and NodeJs with Hapi server in the Back-end. All websites are mobile responsive up to 320px and have all major browser support.
- Developed 5 highly optimized dashboards using ReactJs to help business teams visualize the key performance indicators and other strategic data for the organization at a glance. Made use of latest libraries like Redux, Webpack for code bundling, Sass for CSS pre-processing, and Axios for API calls.
- · Mentored 4 new joiners to help them get on board in the team and trained them well.
- Brought new ideas and improved existing development process by introducing OOP style of programming and training everyone on writing modular code, thus helping in overall reduction of more than 40% in website development time.
- · Actively took interviews and helped to bring new talent to the team. Also responsible for setting up the interview questions and assignments for the candidates.
- Expertise in creating highly optimized Search Engine Results Page with Google DFP/ADX integration along with the integrations of Taboola and Outbrain Ad Units.

Freelance App Developer

07/2020 - 11/2020

• Developed a mobile application with payment gateway integration based on client requirements and specifications using Ionic 4, Laravel and MySQL. The app is deployed and published on Google PlayStore since November 2020. Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=vow.gold.investment

Accenture Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Mumbai, India

Application Development Analyst

08/2016 - 12/2017

- Trained in SAP (Sales and Distribution) module and was part of a support team for the implementation of SAP modules for a very high profiled client based in the USA.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Collaborated with cross-functional development team members to analyze potential system solutions based on evolving client requirements}$
- · Researched and Developed more than 16 Automation tools that helped in saving more than 3000 employee hours.
- Executed full software development life cycle SDLC
- Translated client's business requirements and objectives into technical applications and solutions with their complete documentation
- · Learnt and developed client beneficial tools using languages like java, python, javascript and selenium
- · Identified gaps, issues and worked around solutions in SAP Sales and distribution module implemented for the client
- · Wrote, updated and maintained technical program, end user documentation and operational procedures
- Got Awarded with star employee of the month for 2 consecutive months and was highly praised by my managers and the senior management.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology (B.E - I.T) K.J Somaiya College of Engineering - Vidyavihar, Mumbai, India

2012 - 2016

SKILLS

Website Optimization | Agile and Scrum methodologies | Modular Programming | SEO | Design Patterns and Principles | Effective Communication | Time management

Technical Skills: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, PHP, WordPress, SCSS, ReactJs, AngularJs, MySQL, MongoDb, NodeJs, Photoshop, Laravel, Ionic 4.